A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation photographs FA003
Rockefeller Archive Center
- India
  - Rana, Mansingh (architect) - Memorial to Maulana Azad in Delhi
    arches, gazebo,
  - Fellowships - Scholarships
    portrait of Chunilal K. Madia
  - Nutrition Research Laboratory
    feeding, patients, monkey, hospital beds,
  - Hospital Administration
  - Hookworm 1920-1927
    Hookworm, disease, children, cases, group portrait, treatment, buildings, views, water, latrines, cars, automobiles, transportation,
  - Malaria 1924-1944, 1951
    malaria, disease, cases, cow, bullock, irrigation channel, paddy field, river, tents, huts, housing, houses, bacteria, cells, cans, canisters, tanks, spray guns, chart, water, drainage, fieldwork, buildings,
  - Photos Used in Field Reports - Annual and Semi-annual 1937-1939
    spray can, spraying, water, irrigation, channels, bathing, swimming, fields, views, huts, housing, houses, fieldwork, charts, traps,
  - Photos Used in Field Reports - Annual and Semi-annual 1941-1942
    fields, views, transportation, water, irrigation, well, soil, huts, housing, houses, spray cans, canisters, equipment, buildings, pools, interiors,
  - Photos Used in Manuscripts 1938-1943
    water, canals, well, fields, tennis courts, spraying, pit, map, traps, net, channel, huts, housing,
  - Public Health Demonstrations
  - Health Facilities Personnel
    buildings, street, group portrait,
  - Health Services 1921, 1933, 1938
    drilling, building, compost, soil, trench, rubbish, garbage,
  - Public Health Education 1932-1934
    group portrait, building, interior,
  - Indian School of International Studies - Library
    library, interiors,
  - Indian School of International Studies - Staff Training
    men, staff,
  - Virus Studies 1957-1958
    goats, chicks, sheep, monkey,
  - Administration
    cow, chick, larvae, tick testing, plants, research tent, truck, transportation,
  - Virus Research Center, Poona 1960-61
    ticks, camel, horses, birds, examinations, mosquito larvae, animal testing, library interior, building,
  - Kyasanur - Poona Virus Lab 1957-1958
    maps, chart, doctors, researchers, laboratory, equipment, ticks, monkey hand, examinations, inoculations, shots, treatment, vaccine, cans, views, tree ladder, infected areas,
  - Kyasanur - Visit of Field Team to Epidemic Area
    animal testing, monkeys, autopsy, surgery, examinations,
  - Deccan College Language Research
    speakers, classrooms, students, teachers, equipment, group portrait,
  - Kyasanur 1958, 1960
    virus cells, people, inoculation, shot,
  - Kyasanur 1959
    traps, inoculations, shots, animals, library, monkeys, water buffalo, patients, sheep,,
  - Agriculture -Progress Report, All India Coordinated Rice Improvement Project V.3
    rice field, crops,
  - All-India Institute 1959
    men, people, doctors,
  - All-India Institute 1960
    people, men, speaker,
  - All-India Institute (July 1960 - December 1960)
  - All-India Institute (January 1962 - April 1962)
    Jackie Kennedy, women, men, people, hallway,
  - All-India Institute May 1962
    group portrait, building construction,
  - All-India Institute, Rural Health (January 1963 - April 1963)
    map,
  - All-India Institute, Rural Health (August 1963 - November 1963)
    map, chart,
  - All-India Institute, Rural Health 1964
    map
  - Christian Medical College, Ludhiana - Preventive Medicine (May 1953-May 1955)
    native people, housing, demonstration, drums, medical examinations, water, well, eating, dirt,
  - Balwant Rajput College - Agriculture (1958-1960)
    Dwight E. Eisenhower, car, vehicle, transportation, men, ceremony,
  - Agriculture - Gavindu, H.C.
  - Royal Asiatic Society of Bengal - Dance 1948-1954
    native dresses, costumes, ceremony,
  - Kyasanur - September-October 1957
    room, disease ward,
- Pakistan
  - General
- United Provinces, India
  - Partabgarh Health Unit
- Burma
  - Hookworm
  - Public Health Demonstrations
  - University of Rangoon - Library
    book, shelves, library, interior, reference desk, building,
- Iraq
  - Al-Hikma University
    gate, solar panels, aerial view,
  - Medical Sciences
- New Guinea and Papua - including Solomon Islands
  - General
    Papuan dancing mask, natives,
  - "Fish Stories from Papua" Lambert, S.M., n.d.
    head, face, fish spear, fishing kite, natives,
  - Hookworm - 1
    Hookworm, disease, houses, housing, natives, skulls, headdress, rubber trees, latrines, tools, streets, villages, boats, privy, washing, treatment,
  - Hookworm - 2
    buildings, natives, group photos, street,
  - Lambert, S.M. "Hookworm Disease in the Territory of New Guinea, March 18-Oct.26
    houses, housing, children, village, latrine, building, natives,
  - Ankylostomiasis Infection Survey of British Soloman Islands..." Lambert, S.M.
    boat, natives, dancing, building, village, housing, house, volcano,
  - Lambert, S.M. "Hookworm Disease in Papua.." Survey Report No. 7
    Hookworm, disease, natives, groups, village, huts, housing, houses, street, mill,
  - Hookworm
    hookworm, disease, house, interior, village, natives, group photos, dance, dancing, privies, privy,
  - Public Health Demonstrations
    natives, people, house, housing, dancing, boats, buildings, streets, village, hospital staff, interior, yaws, cases, treatment,
- New Guinea and Papua, Solomon Islands
  - Hookworm
  - Public Health Demonstrations
- Malaysia - including Brunei, Sabah, Sarawak, Singapore
  - University of Malaya - Virology
    laboratory, interior, equipment, inoculation, shots, truck, transportation,
  - General
    natives, people, inspection, building,
  - Medical Sciences
    building, doctors
  - Hospital Administration
    buildings, interiors, hospital beds, patients, group photo, staff, employees, equipment, chamber
  - Hookworm
    hookworm, disease, privy, privies, cases, patients, building, car, automobile, transportation, ravine, water, river, children, group photos, views, carts,
  - Malaria
    estate, housing, ravine, ditches, trenches, drainage, fields, swamps, inspection, treatment, examination, disease, malaria, cases, examples,
  - Medical Sciences
    Group portrait, ceremony,
  - Hospital Administration
    building, street,
  - Hookworm
    classroom, hookworm, disease, house, housing, building, sign, advertisement, latrine, construction, equipment, drilling, digging, group photos, drainage, office interior,
  - Russell, P.F. "Report of a Hookworm and Rural Health Survey of Malaua..."
    river, buildings, latrines, water cart, group portrait, hookworm, disease, cases,
  - Russell - Report of a Hookworm and Rural Health Survey of Penang Settlement..
    village, children, group photo, school, latrine, river, building, hookworm, disease, patient, case
  - Malaria
    drainage, ravine, dam, construction, water pits, canal, channel, men,
  - Public Health Demonstrations
    water reservoir, building, malaria exhibit, men, village, street,
  - School of Hygiene and Public Health
  - Malaria
    group portraits, staff,
  - Hookworm
    concrete latrine slab, construction,
  - Barnes - Report of a Public Health Survey of Sarawak 1926
    buildings, palace, royalty, river, boats, market, bridge, construction, railroad, natives, orang-outang, monkey, village, street, people, aerial view,
  - King Edward VII College of Medicine and Singapore General Hospital
    buildings, view, hospital ward, beds, patients,
- Federated Malay States
  - General
  - Medical Sciences
  - Hospital Administration
  - Hookworm
  - Malaria
- Strait Settlements
  - Medical Sciences
  - Hospital Administration
  - Hookworm
  - Russell, P.F. "Report of a Hookworm and Rural Health Survey of Malaua..."
  - Russell - Report of a Hookworm and Rural Health Survey of Penang Settlement..
  - Malaria
  - Public Health Demonstrations
  - School of Hygiene and Public Health
- Malaya
  - Malaria
- Sarawak
  - Hookworm
  - Barnes - Report of a Public Health Survey of Sarawak 1926
- Singapore
  - King Edward VII College of Medicine and Singapore General Hospital
- Africa
  - Scientific Development
    conference, group portrait, staff, meeting
  - Yellow Fever
  - International Institute of African Languages and Cultures
    animal slaughter, dye pits, infant, baby, people, natives, tools, cattle,
  - Schistosomiasis
- Kenya
  - Health
    examinations, buildings, inoculations, instruction, teaching, huts, patients, students, speaker, ceremony,
  - University College, Fountain / University of East Africa - Library
    library interior, fountain sculpture,
  - Egerton Agricultural College
    cow milking, aerial view, buildings, tractors, instruction, lounge, cattle, crops, laboratory, equipment,
  - Maize Improvement
    view, corn, maize, crops, stalk, field, tractor, equipment, breeding
  - Royal College, Sciences - Veterinary Medicine
    buildings, laboratory, equipment, petrie dish,
  - Siriba Training College
    buildings, cows, people, classroom, group portrait,
  - Wheat Improvement
    greenhouses, plants, buildings, tractor, equipment,
  - Wheat Improvement (Njoro, Kenya)
    aerial views, farms, fields,
  - University College - Economics
    students, professor, teacher,
  - University of Nairobi - Veterinary Medicine
    surgery, natives, disease, hydatidosis, patients, children, water hole, dry riverbed,
- East Africa Region
  - East African Yellow Fever Commission
    interior, laboratory, buildings, car, automobile, transportation, office,
  - Cacso-Cauro
    mobile laboratory, truck, transportation, equipment, carcass, hunting, shooting, examination,
  - East African Agricultural Organization Animal Science-Soil Biology-SoilChemistry
    scale, hunting, giraffe, gun, mobile laboratory, truck, transportation, equipment, buildings, greenhouses, animals,
  - Yellow Fever
    injection, microscopes, research, testing,
  - University of East Africa - Housing 1964-1966
  - University of East Africa - Housing 1966-1968
  - Makerere College - Agriculture (January - March 1967)
    tractor, farm equipment, machinery,
  - Hookworm
    hut, house, housing, latrine, people, children, hookworm, disease, cases, group photo,
- East Africa - Seychelles
  - Hookworm
- Mauritius
  - Hookworm
    people, latrines, huts, buildings, houses, housing, sugar factory, equipment, truck, cart, transportation, children, group photos, hookworm, disease, cases,
- Rhodesia
  - University College of Rhodesia and Nyasaland - Agriculture and Zoology
    field work, cotton, tools, laboratory, equipment, building, maize leafs,
  - University College of Rhodesia and Nyasaland - Library
  - University College of Rhodesia and Nyasaland - Zoology 1959-1961
    apparatus, dragging, collection of larvae ticks,
- North Africa Region
  - Nigeria 1930's
    students, doctor, laboratory, field,
  - Egyptian Service of Antiquities - Habachi, Labib 1955
    tablet, writing, heiroglyphics, egyptian writing,
- South Africa Region
  - Virus Research
    tree climbing, sampling, traps, laboratory, equipment, injections, inoculations, shots, animals, testing, examination, transportation, boat, ferry, truck, airplane, library,
  - Hospital Administration
    buildings, views,
  - Virus Laboratory Activities
    tree climbing, mosquito catching, laboratory, equipment, animal testing, traps, veterinary officer, inspectors, roping, bleeding, monkey, sampling, examination, inoculations, shots, natives, airplane, transportation, ferry, supplies, river, camp, dancing, stick fighting,
  - Capetown - South African Institute for Medicine
    buildings, cadaver, dissecting, students, interior, classroom, record room, hospital, beds, laboratory, equipment, supplies, rabbits, cages, waiting room,
  - University of Witwatersrand
    hospital beds, dining hall, buildings, cribs, nurses, children, patients,
  - University of Natal - University of Witwatersrand
    dissection room, building, group portrait, students, library interior, lecture hall, cages, guniea pigs, records, laboratory, x-rays, washing machines, power room, therapy, treatment, storage, patients, hospital beds,
  - University of Pretoria - Plant Physiology 1947-1951
    plants, roots, corms, buds, seedlings,
  - Department of Foreign Affairs - Library
    library interior,
- South African Region - Swaziland
  - Department of Foreign Affairs - Library
- Republic of South Africa
  - General
    children, natives, cart, wagon, transportation, meat, building, kitchen, store, interior, huts, bushman painting,
  - South African Snail Survey
  - Virus Diseases
  - University of Pretoria Plant Physiology
    building, construction, duct, air conditioning units, temperature chart,
- Uganda
  - General
    native, infant, baby, child,
  - Makerere University, Medical School Equipment - Preventive Medicine
    destruction, damage, laboratory, interior, staff, students, buildings, testing, examinations, natives,
  - East African Agriculture & Forestry Research Org./Makerere College, Agriculture
    fields, stalks, soybeans, research, collecting, building,
  - Yellow Fever
    buildings, examination, natives, landscape, road, tree ladder, views,
  - Makerere College - African Music
    classroom, students, drum,
  - Makerere College - Economics
    classroom, teacher, students, professor
  - [CLOSED] Banda, Babwebona Karomba E.J. 1969-1974
    portrait,
  - Makerere College - Bradley, David J. 1966-1970
    water sources, holes, river, buildings, natives, road, map,
- Sudan
  - University of Khartoum
    farmer, field, irrigation, ditch, sugar cane, workers,
  - Medical Sciences
    classroom, students, laboratory, buildings, library, baby animal,
  - University of Khartoum - Agriculture
    plants, laboratory, equipment, classroom, students, chickens, tractor, farming, plowing, oxen, cows, vehicles, transportation, animal examination, dissection,
  - Hookworm
    steamer ship, passengers, vendors,
- West African Region
  - General
    natives, market, street, washing, trees, village, buildings, roads, flowers, animals, water pool, buildings, pounding, praying, beach, stone, ceremony, idols, temple,
  - West Africa Fisheries Research Institute
  - Medical Sciences
  - Public Health Demonstrations
  - Knights - Report on Sanitary Conditions in Spanish Guinea, Africa
    family, natives, path, logs, forrest clearing, trees,
  - Yellow Fever - 1
    buildings, boats, river, pots, drainage, huts, natives, village, houses, housing, water tank, cages, market, doctors, diseased cells, organs, lungs, animal examination, laboratory,
  - Yellow Fever - 2
    doctors, laboratory, equipment, natives, water pumping, flooding, exterior, interior, gravestone, monkey, organs, boat, refrigerator, praying, group portraits, buildings, mushroom, staff,
  - Yellow Fever - 3
    monkey, testing, market, boats, transportation, natives, children,
  - West African Yellow Fever Commission - Third Annual Report
  - West African Yellow Fever Commission - Fourth Annual Report
    transportation, cars, automobiles, vehicles,
  - Eddey, Leslie George 1953-1955
    bridge, dam, waterfall,
  - Fabiyi, Akinyele 1957-1959
    charts,
  - Lovanium University 1955-1956
    group portrait,
  - University College, Ibadan - Pediatrics 1960-1961
    charts, diagrams, map, damaged corn,
  - University College, Ibadan - Pediatrics 1965-1970
    children, examinations, charts, natives, poultry pen, pond, group portrait,
  - University College, Ibadan - Pediatrics (Supplementary Material) 1964-1965
    food demonstration, charts,
- Ghana
  - Ghana Experimental Theatre
    building, acting, actors, performances, sets, construction,
  - University College of Ghana - African Studies
    musicians, musical instruments, drums, recorders,
  - University of Ghana - Sutherland, Efwa T. 1963-1967
    village, exteriors, drummers, natives, crowd, audience, women,
- Nigeria
  - University College, Ibadan
    buildings, library, student, idol,
  - University College, Ibadan - African Studies
    student, library, idol,
  - University College, Ibadan - Agriculture
    cow, milking, field, pasture, stalks, palm trees, testing, research,
  - University of Ibadan - Axworthy
    equipment, people,
  - University College, Ibadan - Drama
    actor, masks,
  - University of Ibadan - Ifemesia
    man, professor, teacher,
  - University College, Ibadan - Library
  - University College, Ibadan - Rural Training
    natives, building, vehicle, views, water well, village, speaker, ceremony, inauguration, people, telecommunication mast,
  - University of Ibadan - Ministry Luncheon
    men, group photo,
  - University College, Ibadan - Nutrition/Pediatrics/Psychiatry
    natives, people, map, child, examination, doctor, patient,
  - University of Ibadan - Faculty
    professors, men,
  - University of Ibadan - Nursing Department
    women, library, building, instruction, speakers, ceremony, group photo, natives, dancing, musical instruments, drum, celebration,
  - Northern Region Experimental Station
    farm work, barrels, oxen, fields, production, equipment,
  - Sorghum
    fields, stalks, inspection, sorghum,
  - University College, Ibadan - Broiler House
  - Yellow Fever
    automobiles, cars, vehicles
  - Beier, H.V. - Experimental Art School, Mbari Oshogbo
    artists, paintings, painters, artwork,
  - Ogunmola Theatre
    set, actors, play, stage,
  - University College, Ibadan - Arabic and Islamic Studies
    men, library, books,
  - Social Sciences
  - University of Ibadan - Economics
  - University of Ibadan - Virus Laboratory / Research
    buildings, containers, equipment, laboratory, staff, examination,
  - University College, Ibadan - Drama 1966-1967
  - University College, Ibadan - Supplementary Material 1959
    microscopic images, cells,
  - University of Ibadan - Akinkugbe, Oladipo Olujimi 1965-1966, 1968
    equipment, machinery, apparatus, retinal vessels,
  - University of Ibadan - Nutrition 1963-1964, 1966, 1969-1971
    food demonstration,
  - University of Ibadan - Legume Entomology 1968-1975
    charts, fields, plants, crops,
  - [CLOSED] Braide, Victor Bowerson-Chase 1968-1970
    diagram,
  - [CLOSED] Olowe, Olukayode 1971-1973
    portrait attached to fellowship/scholarship application,
  - [CLOSED] Sanda, Akinade Olu 1968-1970
  - University of Ibadan 1967, 1972
    charts, x-ray, pelvis, bladder,
- Sierra Leone
  - West Africa Fisheries Research Institute
- France
  - General 1928-1952
    park, building, interior, office, projection, screeening room, laboratory, equipment, arches, construction,
  - Police Systems
  - Association Pour La Sante Mentale de L'Enface 1952-1953
    consultation, examination, nurses, staff, children, toys, testing, library,
  - College de France - Monkey Station (Algeria) 1949, 1956
    views, tank, monkey, examination, testing, buildings, cages, gate,
  - Institut Pasteur
    office, laboratory, interior, equipment,
  - Lyons University - Faculty of Medicine 1927,1930,1959
    doctors, men, women, view, buildings, faculty, staff, professors,
  - University of Marseilles - Neurobiological Laboratory
    laboratory, interior, equipment, jars,
  - University of Paris - Neurosurgery
    cells, staff group portrait, surgery, hospital beds, nurses, operating room, interior, examination, preparation, patients,
  - Hospital Administration
    hospital cribs, lecture hall, operating room, equipment, buildings, dining room, nurses, interiors,
  - Nursing
    staff group portrait, buildings, interiors, office, nurses, patients, bedroom, classroom, examination, education,
  - Banyuls - Marine Biology
    views, buildings,
  - College de France - Joliot
    equipment, machine,
  - Pasteur Institute - Microbiology
    laboratory, equipment, research, experiments,
  - University of Lyons - Atomic Physics 1944,1946
    laboratory, equipment, machinery, hallways, building, destruction, damage,
  - Public Health Demonstrations
    buildings, medical staff, examinations, equipment, interiors, offices, files,
  - Soissous Health Center
    examinations, children, women, interviews, consultations,
  - Institute of Hygiene - Faculty of Medicine, Paris
    buildings, interior, vacant rooms,
  - General
  - Musee de L'Homme
    library interior, desks, shelves, books, card catalog,
  - Institut de Science Economique Applique
    library, meetings, conference, office,
  - Tuberculosis Commission 1919-1924, 1938
    transporation, rail car, equipment, machinery, interior, ceremony, speech, exhibit, medical offices, staff, buildings, patients, treatment,
  - Tuberculosis Commission 1918 - 1
    school children, exhibit, examination, medical office, men, officers, housing, houses, homes, buildings, streets, staff, cardinal,
  - Tuberculosis Commission 1918 - 2
    streets, buildings, views, children, instruction, crowds, car, vehicle, transportation, automobile, exhibit, refugees, river,
  - Tuberculosis Commission 1918 - 3
    children, canal, water, families, buildings, views, villages, people, group portrait, dispensary, medal, drawing, vehicle, transportation, cars, automobiles,
  - Tuberculosis Commission 1918 - 4
    clinic, laboratory, buildings, interiors, vehicle, automobile, car, exhibit, demonstration, children, patients, hospitals, group photos, watershed, cows, views, construction, train, packages,
  - Tuberculosis Prevention Posters - Prints
    posters,
  - [CLOSED] Association pour la Sante Mentale de L'Enfrance, Paris 1951-1959
    portraits,
  - Institut des Hauntes Estudes Chinoises - Tibetan Studies 1959-1965
- Algeria
  - Yellow Fever
    children, dusting,
- Corsica
  - Anti-Malaria Application Station, Bastia
    views, scenery, landscape, buildings, river, aqueducts, lake, bridges, breeding places,
  - Malaria
    hut, people, hatchery, canal, ditch, spraying, water, tanks, malaria, disease, infection, equipment, apparatus, children, drainage,
- Laos
  - Foreign Affairs - Books
    painting, mural, library, interior, books, shelves,
- French West Africa
  - General
    camels, basket, wharf, buildings, views,
  - Medical Sciences
    group portrait, medical students,
  - Nursing
    nurses, nursing students, group photo, girls, females,
  - Hospital Administration
    cliff, building, view,
  - Yellow Fever
    equipment, apparatus, fumigation, boat, huts, water supply systems, well, market, conference, meeting, group photo, slave dungeon, buildings,
- Ivory Coast
  - Yellow Fever
- Mali
  - Animal Husbandry Station
    agriculture, farming, crops, chickens, cows, tractor, machinery, equipment, stalks, workers, anti-parasite bath,
- Senegal
  - University of Dakar - African History
    aerial views, landscape,
- New Hebrides
  - General
    pig, sacrifice, stone, idols, drums, jaws, tusks, altar, masks, tool, police, cloth, spirits, leprosy, sabre shins, disease, infection,
  - Hookworm
    Hookworm, speciman examination, disease, natives, groups, treatment, lectures, cows, huts, homes, houses, housing, men, women, children,
  - Yaws
    yaws, disease, faces,
- Martinique and Guadeloupe
  - General
    mountain, lava, Mt. Pelee, views, buildings, port,
  - Humanities and Arts
- Asia
  - General
    group portrait, models, tanks, exercise, field day, bazaar, crowds, town square, buildings, tug-of-war, bread biting, speakers,
  - Administration
    group portrait, ground breaking ceremony, turning sod, men, woman, meeting, conference,
  - Educational Commission - University of Chicago, Report Volume 4, Part 6
    river, boats, views, buildings, houseboat, islands, mountains, valleys, people, streets, temple interior, family, memorial arches, houses, homes, housing, bridges, rice fields, children, water wheel, water buffalo, plow construction, road, military, cliff, Peking, Mongolia, Great Wall of China, transporation, vehicles,
  - Notes of 1915 Trip - Victor G. Heiser
  - Notes of 1916 Trip Volume 1 and 2 - Victor G. Heiser
  - Population Problems